This is a work in process.
[AI] 这是一项正在进行的工作。
based on some comments that were made at TED two years ago
[AI] 根据两年前TED上的一些评论
about the need for the storage of vaccine.
[AI] 关于疫苗储存的必要性。
(Video): [On this planet
[AI] （视频）：[在这个星球上]
1.6 billion people
[AI] 16亿人
don't have access to electricity
[AI] 没有电
refrigeration
[AI] 冷藏
or stored fuels
[AI] 或储存的燃料
this is a problem
[AI] 这是一个问题
it impacts:
[AI] 它影响：
the spread of disease
[AI] 疾病的传播
the storage of food and medicine
[AI] 食品和药品的储存
and the quality of life.
[AI] 以及生活质量。
So here's the plan ... inexpensive refrigeration
[AI] 这就是计划。。。廉价制冷
that doesn't use electricity. propane. gas. kerosene or consumables
[AI] 那不需要电。丙烷。气体煤油或消耗品
time for some thermodynamics
[AI] 是时候学点热力学了
And the story of the Intermittent Absorption Refrigerator]
[AI] 还有间歇性吸收式制冷机的故事]
Adam Grosser: So 29 years ago. I had this thermo teacher
[AI] 亚当·格罗瑟：那么29年前。我有一个老师
who talked about absorption and refrigeration. one of those things
[AI] 他谈到了吸收和制冷。其中之一
that stuck in my head. a lot like the Stirling engine:
[AI] 那件事一直萦绕在我的脑海里。很像斯特林发动机：
it was cool. but you didn't know what to do with it.
[AI] 很酷。但你不知道该怎么办。
It was invented in 1858. by this guy Ferdinand Carré.
[AI] 它是1858年发明的。这是费迪南德·卡雷写的。
but he couldn't actually build anything with it
[AI] 但他不能用它来建造任何东西
because of the tools at the time.
[AI] 因为当时的工具。
This crazy Canadian named Powel Crosley commercialized this thing
[AI] 一个叫鲍威尔·克罗斯利的疯狂加拿大人把这件事商业化了
called the IcyBall. in 1928.
[AI] 称为冰球。1928年。
It was a really neat idea. and I'll get to why it didn't work.
[AI] 这真是个好主意。我会解释为什么它不起作用。
but here's how it works.
[AI] 但这是它的工作原理。
There's two spheres and they're separated in distance.
[AI] 有两个球体，它们在距离上是分开的。
One has a working fluid. water and ammonia.
[AI] 一个有工作液。水和氨。
and the other is a condenser.
[AI] 另一个是冷凝器。
You heat up one side. the hot side.
[AI] 你加热一边。热的一面。
The ammonia evaporates and it recondenses in the other side.
[AI] 氨蒸发后在另一侧再凝结。
You let it cool to room temperature.
[AI] 你让它冷却到室温。
and then. as the ammonia reevaporates and combines with the water
[AI] 然后。当氨重新蒸发并与水结合时
back on the erstwhile hot side.
[AI] 回到从前的热点。
it creates a powerful cooling effect.
[AI] 它产生了强大的冷却效果。
So it was a great idea that didn't work at all.
[AI] 所以这是一个根本不起作用的好主意。
They blew up.
[AI] 他们爆炸了。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
Because you're using ammonia. you get hugely high pressures
[AI] 因为你用的是氨水。你会感受到巨大的压力
if you heated them wrong;
[AI] 如果你加热错误；
it topped 400 psi.
[AI] 它达到了400磅/平方英寸。
The ammonia was toxic. it sprayed everywhere.
[AI] 氨是有毒的。到处都是。
But it was kind of an interesting thought.
[AI] 但这是一个有趣的想法。
So the great thing about 2006.
[AI] 2006年最棒的事情。
there's a lot of really great computational work you can do.
[AI] 你可以做很多非常棒的计算工作。
So we got the whole thermodynamics department at Stanford involved --
[AI] 所以我们让斯坦福大学的整个热力学系都参与进来了--
a lot of computational fluid dynamics.
[AI] 大量的计算流体力学。
We proved that most of the ammonia refrigeration tables are wrong.
[AI] 我们证明了大多数氨制冷表是错误的。
We found some nontoxic refrigerants
[AI] 我们发现了一些无毒的制冷剂
that worked at very low vapor pressures.
[AI] 在非常低的蒸汽压下工作。
We brought in a team from the UK --
[AI] 我们从英国引进了一支队伍--
a lot of great refrigeration people. it turns out. in the UK --
[AI] 很多很棒的人。事实证明。在英国--
and built a test rig. and proved that. in fact.
[AI] 建造了一个试验台。并证明了这一点。事实上
we could make a low-pressure. nontoxic refrigerator.
[AI] 我们可以制造一个低压。无毒冰箱。
So this is the way it works.
[AI] 这就是它的工作方式。
You put it on a cooking fire.
[AI] 你把它放在炉火上。
Most people have cooking fires in the world.
[AI] 世界上大多数人都有炉火。
whether it's camel dung or wood.
[AI] 不管是骆驼粪还是木头。
It heats up for about 30 minutes. cools for an hour.
[AI] 加热大约30分钟。冷却一小时。
You put it into a container and it will refrigerate for 24 hours.
[AI] 你把它放在一个容器里，它会冷藏24小时。
It looks like this.
[AI] 看起来像这样。
This is the fifth prototype. it's not quite done.
[AI] 这是第五个原型。还没做完。
It weighs about eight pounds. and this is the way it works.
[AI] 它重约八磅。这就是它的工作方式。
You put it into a 15-liter vessel. about three gallons.
[AI] 你把它放进一个15升的容器里。大约三加仑。
and it'll cool it down to just above freezing --
[AI] 它会把温度降到冰点以上--
three degrees above freezing --
[AI] 冰点以上三度--
for 24 hours in a 30 degree C environment.
[AI] 在30摄氏度的环境中持续24小时。
It's really cheap.
[AI] 它真的很便宜。
We think we can build these in high volumes for about 25 dollars.
[AI] 我们认为我们可以用25美元左右的价格大量生产这些产品。
in low volumes for about 40 dollars.
[AI] 以大约40美元的低价出售。
And we think we can make refrigeration something that everybody can have.
[AI] 我们认为我们可以让制冷成为每个人都能拥有的东西。
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）